# **Alexey Alexeev**

DevOps enthusiast, QA Lead and Test Manager

voodoo144@yandex.ru

## Summary

Big experience with auto testing tools like Selenium/WebDriver, Watir, AutoIt, SoapUI, JMeter, MActor, Codeception, Mink. Fitnesse Programming Languages: Java, C++, PHP, Scala, Groovy, Ruby Experience with development for Apache Camel, OrientDb, DerbyDB Testing tools creation/development Experience with integration testing. JUnit, TestNG, TestUnit, PhpUnit Experience with IBM WebSphere Product Family. CI: TeamCity, Jenkins, Luntbuild, Bamboo BT: Jira, Redmine Test Management Tools: TestLink, Spiratest, Zephir ServiceBus: TIBCO/rvd Experience with Apache Solr, Tomcat, Nginx Specialization: testing, test automation, deploy/delivery automation.

## Experience

### Software Test Manager at Luxoft

January 2014 - Present (1 year 9 months)

QA/Devops work for customers( high load infra and trading applications), qa and test-management, test environment management and maintenance. Auto-test development with Fitnesse framework Automatization of deploy processess. Server management tools: Ansible Log management: logstash/kibana Monitoring: monit Service Discovery: apache zookeeper CI: Jenkins Test Management: TestRail

### QA Team Lead at Svyaznoy CR

August 2013 - December 2013 (5 months)

Managing QA Team, close working with SQA and SRE team. Developing deployment lifecycle. Developing integration layer between Jira and auto-tests. Server management tools: Chef Log management: logstash/kibana Monitoring: zabbix Auto test language: php/ruby/java Databases: postgres, redis

1 recommendation available upon request

#### Senior Automation QA at Svyaznoy

October 2012 - August 2013 (11 months)

Auto-tests development, auto-tests maintenance. Improving auto-tests execution time (changed from 3 hours to 20 minutes) Language: php CI: Jenkins Framework: web-driver / yii

### Senior Specialist at Neoflex

February 2012 - October 2012 (9 months)

Senior specialist in automation qua department. Implementation auto-tests framework based on WebDriver. Translation manual test cases to automated cases. Teaching another qua specialist in company. Test Management: Spiratest Language: java Framework: web-driver

1 recommendation available upon request

### Automation Test Engineer at Molotok.Ru

July 2011 - January 2012 (7 months)

Developing automation tests, framework for automation tests,

### Automation Test Engineer at Allegro MAIL.RU eCommerce Group

2011 - 2012 (1 year)

auto-tests developing

2 recommendations available upon request

### QA Test Engineer at XIM

December 2010 - July 2011 (8 months)

### Courses

### **Software Test Manager**

Luxoft

Time-management

Problem solving and decision making

**Investment Banking** 

## Organizations

#### **Tester's Life**

Main editor of automatization articles

January 2013 to Present

#### **Publications**

#### Modern web automatization

Tester's Life December 2012

Authors: Alexey Alexeev

In this article I try to describe all modern ways to automate web application testings

#### Sikuli - universal tester's instrument

Tester's Life August 2013

Authors: Alexey Alexeev

Article about interresting gui-based instrument Sikuli

### Successful git branching model

Tester's Life April 2014

Authors: Alexey Alexeev

This is russian translation of article http://nvie.com/posts/a-successful-git-branching-model/

## **Projects**

### **Openwave Amplicity**

December 2010 to July 2011

Members: Alexey Alexeev, Alexey Andreev

### **Page Object Generator**

December 2012 to Present

Members: Alexey Alexeev

#### **BrandsAndBrands**

July 2011 to January 2012

Members: Alexey Alexeev, Alexey Tkach

### **Yopolis**

May 2012 to Present

Members: Alexey Alexeev, Evgeny Danilov, Eugene Fedorov

#### **Neoflex FrontOffice**

February 2012 to October 2012

Members: Alexey Alexeev, Alexey Tkach

### Jenkins Redmine Plugin

2013 to 2013

Members: Alexey Alexeev

### **Foodregator**

December 2013 to Present

Members: Alexey Alexeev

#### **QA Consulting**

November 2014 to Present

Members: Alexey Alexeev

## Languages

**English** 

(Full professional proficiency)

Russian

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

## Skills & Expertise

Scrum

**Testing** 

**Subversion** 

**JIRA** 

**Software Project Management** 

**Agile Methodologies** 

**Requirements Analysis** 

**Test Planning** 

Linux

Software Development Agile Project Management

Git

Java

Scala

**PHP** 

**PHPUnit** 

Redmine

**Play Framework** 

Heroku

**Jelastic** 

OOP

FP

Ant

Maven

**Dart** 

### Education

## Obninsk Institute of Atomic Energy at National Nuclear Research University "MEPhI"

Master's degree, Applied Mathemathics, 2005 - 2011

Grade: 4

Protvino school #3

### **Interests**

QA, CI, CD, server management, log management, web-development, people management, qa management

# **Alexey Alexeev**

DevOps enthusiast, QA Lead and Test Manager

voodoo144@yandex.ru



## 4 people have recommended Alexey

"Aleksey - one of the best qa manager and qa lead I ever work with. He has good technical background and good soft skills. His sweet disposition helps him to avoid conflicts in team."

— Yana Zolotareva, managed Alexey

— Alexey Vorobyev, QA Lead, Neoflex, managed Alexey at Neoflex

— **Dmitri Vlasov**, *HR manager*, *Allegro MAIL.RU eCommerce Group*, *LLC "e-commerce group"*, managed Alexey indirectly at Allegro MAIL.RU eCommerce Group

"Alexey is exellent professional in area of QA. He is initiative, dynamic & self - development driven. It was great to work with him. Recommend Alexey as high qualified specialist."

— Ann Amosova, Head of HR&development, Molotok.Ru/ Allegro Mail.ru e-Commerce Group, worked with Alexey at Allegro MAIL.RU eCommerce Group

Contact Alexey on LinkedIn